<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-02-06T19:03:33-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">untitled</title><subtitle>my corner of the internet, where i post ideas about the things i enjoy and document my curiosity</subtitle><entry><title type="html">New Climbing Gym in Akron, OH</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/chinese%20blog/2022/01/28/blog-2-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Climbing Gym in Akron, OH" /><published>2022-01-28T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/chinese%20blog/2022/01/28/blog-2-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/chinese%20blog/2022/01/28/blog-2-2.html"><![CDATA[<p>今年我决定了一个目标，就是更多地去攀岩场。 说实话，我比我理想的更不适合。 因为我喜欢它，每周爬一次给了我一个变得更强壮的理由。</p>

<p>上个星期，我开始了实现这一目标，参观了我在俄亥俄州的第一个攀岩馆。 这是我住在的地方以北45分钟的开车，所以这对我来说是一个时间承诺。 然而，那里的车程是宁静祥和的，所以我自己享受了额外的时间。 我想着我的一周，听有声读物，听音乐。</p>

<p>房本身不是很大。 说实话，我想家乡的大城市，因为它提供了更大的空间和更多的人。 那个健身房由2个攀岩墙组成，可是家里的攀岩一般有5到10个。 此外,传统的VX方法没有对这些路线进行评级. 相反，健身房有自己的评级系统，松散地对应于VX评级。 这让很难了解我的进展，原因很难解释。</p>

<p>我在健身房一共花了2个小时。 有些是用来爬山的，有些是用来举重的。 那里的人大部分都很善良，我希望回到墙上爬。 我要把它作为我周末例行公事的一部分！</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="chinese blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[今年我决定了一个目标，就是更多地去攀岩场。 说实话，我比我理想的更不适合。 因为我喜欢它，每周爬一次给了我一个变得更强壮的理由。]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Review: Don’t Look Up</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/review/2022/01/23/blog-2-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Review: Don’t Look Up" /><published>2022-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-01-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/review/2022/01/23/blog-2-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/review/2022/01/23/blog-2-1.html"><![CDATA[<p>周末上我有机会看这部具有社会意义的电影，想应该讨论这些主题对美国文化的影响。</p>

<p>首先必须 给出一个简单的前提概述。 两位美国科学家发现彗星会撞击地球并杀死所有人类文明和地球生命，尝试建议领导们停止它。 然而，由于官僚激励和不正的媒体资本制度，警告被忽视，世界注定要失败。</p>

<p>非常明显的，这个故事是气候变化真实威胁的故事。 我嘲笑新闻媒体怎么报道这场灾难的荒谬和准确性。 生活在大流行病中，那些在社会危机中工作的人对我来说是真实的。</p>

<p>但我相信这部电影是美国独有的。 其他国家已经开始了解与应对气候变化和其他社会灾难，但美国的个人主义阻碍它。 很明显，拯救世界的公共必要性不能通过个人自由的意识形态来解释，但美国时代精神不能了解这一点。 相反，美国人为自己的行为找借口，用非理性，并说每一个对文明的生存威胁称为”骗局”。</p>

<p>最后，我想谈出这部电影创作的内部矛盾。 整整情节围绕着改变和沟通的表演性的现代想法。 事实它呼吁所谓的”进步”概念”对权力说真话。”其实为电影提供资金的拥有阶级预防反资本主义应对气候变化的系统性努力：他们有兴趣把变化转化作为商品。 在现实中，他们不听科学家提出的警告。</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="review" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[周末上我有机会看这部具有社会意义的电影，想应该讨论这些主题对美国文化的影响。]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">3 basic reasons to oppose American capitalism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/political/2021/12/08/blog-1-13.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3 basic reasons to oppose American capitalism" /><published>2021-12-08T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-12-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/political/2021/12/08/blog-1-13</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/political/2021/12/08/blog-1-13.html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <p>我认为关心社会和世界公民的美国人应该支持社会主义和共产主义。首先，我想介绍美国的收入不平等和阶级对立问题。然后，我谈起美国经济和社会变革之间的历史关系。接下来，我讨论资本主义与环保对立，注意商品生产的坏处。最后，我鼓励读者考虑支持社会制度。</p>
  </blockquote>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <blockquote>
    <p>过去几年中，美国收入不平等越来越严重。最富有百分之十个资本家现在拥有美国全部财富的百分之七十。尽管美国有“辛苦地劳动才能富有”的常话，但其实只有资本才能创造更多的资本。这样我们的国家是建立在资产阶级和工人阶级之间的对立。例如、美洲原住民种族灭绝、种族主义和性别歧视都是资本主义生产方式的结果。为了增加利润，资本家危害世界。仅仅重新分配财富不够。为了创造变革，公民必须抓住生产资料。</p>
  </blockquote>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>社会主义在美国并不新鲜。十九世纪末，大量工人举行罢工威胁了政治制度后，美国劳工部才被成立了。二十世纪中，黑人解放运动（尤其黑豹党）一直关注压迫的经济力量。其实，黑人政治作家W.E.B Du Bois与毛泽东会面讨论社会主义问题。肯定在今天，像#LandBack这样的还土地财产运动勇敢地挑战传统的财产权。正如中国共产党历史上保护公民免受帝国主义与封建主义的伤害，美国人也必须帮助国外人民免受美国政策的压迫而反对我们资本政府。</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>为什么必须改变资本制度呢？因为它毁灭了世界！世界公民团结起来拯救环境！美国的工业为了利润开发生态资源。可是如果有利可图的话，资本家没有很好地管理生态资源。相比之下，由于社会主义将安全的社会作为最重要的目标，它并不是这样。中国社会主义已经开始通过植树造林和碳中和政策拯救地球。由于中国强力的中央集政府与计划，共产党可以有效地管理国家的权力，以此停气候变化。</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>社会要进步，就必须建成共产社会。 资本的积累不公平地压抑世界人民。 正如毛泽东认识推翻中国封建制度的必要性，我们也必须发现推翻资本主义和美帝国主义的必要性。 未来不可预知，但人民生存必然。希望大家考虑支持社会主义。</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="political" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[我认为关心社会和世界公民的美国人应该支持社会主义和共产主义。首先，我想介绍美国的收入不平等和阶级对立问题。然后，我谈起美国经济和社会变革之间的历史关系。接下来，我讨论资本主义与环保对立，注意商品生产的坏处。最后，我鼓励读者考虑支持社会制度。]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kendrick Lamars Problem Of Evil</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/01/Kendrick-Lamars-Problem-of-Evil.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kendrick Lamars Problem Of Evil" /><published>2020-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/01/Kendrick-Lamars-Problem-of-Evil</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/01/Kendrick-Lamars-Problem-of-Evil.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>**The Lord Shall Smite Thee!: Kendrick Lamar’s Problem of Evil**</strong>
How could a loving God allow suffering? Theologians have considered such a question for hundreds of years. As one struggles through the senseless fears, abuses, and pains of life, it is only natural to question why an all-loving God would allow massive evil. Kendrick Lamar Duckworth, a contemporary rap artist, explores the implications of communicating evil in his track “FEAR.” from the 2018 Pulitzer Prize for Music winning album “DAMN.” The album as a whole employs grand instrumentals, creative lyricism, and experimental progrogression techniques to explore social issues that face the black community, and tangentially, Lamar’s reaction to his own successful life. “FEAR.” specifically centers around a fictional version of Kendrick and his uncle that share a distant yet caring relationship. The author is an artist and social critic, Lamar himself, addressing social issues in the world and in Compton; His foil is Carl Duckworth, Lamar’s cousin, a Balck Hebrew Israelite pastor in the Compton community.  In his track, “FEAR.,” Lamar uses flashback storytelling, hymn-like incantation, and religious allegory, as well as juxtaposition with Judaic theodicies, in order to show that biblical suffering throughout his life contradicts the existence of an all-loving God.
Lamar uses incantations that resemble religious prayer and preach in order to present the perspective that his life is in contradiction to the existence of an all-loving God. In his chorus, Lamar presents a plea to God which is sung both forwards and backwards. “Why God, why God do I gotta suffer? Pain in my heart carry burdens full of struggle” (Lamar 15-16) The voice of these lines is pleading to God for an answer; why must God allow Lamar to go through so much suffering? And if God is omnibenevolent as described by the prevailing religion in Lamar’s community, does that mean that Lamar’s suffering is illegitimate? It is implied that his pain is both physical and mental, and that has been continuous throughout his life. Perhaps Lamar has concluded that the religions around him provide no real answer to the problems that he faces, but that they do provide others with reassurance. It is also evident that Kendrick does not currently see his tribulations as justified, because he has attempted to love and engage with those around him. Lamar’s delivery is reminiscent of his implicit experiences in church, in that it reminds the listener of prayer or hymn singing. When repeated backwards, the lines transform into tongues, which allows the voice to change from Lamar’s into a more theologically knowledgeable identity. The song is meant to be interpreted as a critique of religion as a solution to non-existential fear, and its ability to solve immediate suffering. Ultimately though, the questions presented in the chorus as a whole set up a context for Kendrick’s rumination on his past.
Duckworth also explicates the suffering of his early life through flashback storytelling and lyrical repetition, in order to prove its contrast to the belief in an omnibenevolent God. In the opening verse of the song, after Carl Duckworth has just called to explain the existence of God, Kendrick raps an imitation of his mother’s threats of violent punishment for wrongdoing during childhood. “Go back outside, I beat yo’ ass, lil’ nigga. That homework better be finished, I beat yo’ ass. Your teachers better not be bitchin’ ‘bout you in class” (Lamar 35-37) His mother here represents the God that judges and punishes him for doing poorly, which confuses young Kendrick. This recollection gives rise to the author’s theme that loving gods often have contradictory goals: here, for instance, his mother’s punishment gets in the way of his capacity to fulfill her requirements. Although she loves Kendrick, she uses violence as the answer. This is in his view flawed, and is the result of societal expectations (monetary value, education, etc.), perhaps in the same way that people project their own values onto the idea of god. Either way, Kendrick reminisces on the impact this had on his life: it created a sense of paranoia because his mother’s domestic abuse taught him perverse trust. This has caused him continuous “FEAR.” even to this day, hence the name of the track. Applied to theology, Kendrick shows that God is a construct of society, and that punishment by God is not loving or good, but instead perverse. The punishment by his allegorical God itself (violent beating) and its necessity mentioned by Carl show that the world is not Good, and instead apathetic to the phenomena of both good and evil. The poetic representation of the author’s difficult childhood is used as a means to juxtapose a hopeful existential belief in a higher power.
The artist employs stark juxtaposition of his and Carl’s existential beliefs in order to demonstrate the absurdity of a belief in an all-good God. Lamar is explicitly discussing the themes of his music that are the most popular amongst listeners, specifically his existential fears of being an artist and living an improper life. “’Cause my DNA won’t let me involve in the light of God / I’m talkin’ fear, fear that my humbleness is gone / I’m talkin’ fear, fear that love ain’t livin’ here no more / I’m talkin’ fear, fear that it’s wickedness or weakness” (Lamar 110-113). The character here is discussing the implications of the Christian utopian mindset to strive for a better, more loving future. Here Carl’s ideology is juxtaposed with Kendrick’s childhood; his pedagogy and social pressure prohibits him from being holy. Furthermore, Carl’s identity as a Black Hebrew Israelite reveals to Kendrick that despite his success, there are still divine conflicts in his life. In Carl’s view Kendrick has an implied choice to resolve his fears: either go against the teachings of God, and be evil yet powerful and strong in the face of a difficult life, or follow them and find existential power yet lack social clout or the ability to defend himself from danger. Lamar attempts to resolve these contradictions in the line “Love ain’t living here no more” which has two interpretations. Either he must leave the cursed environment of his past in favor of an Enlightened future, or that there is no Enlightened future at all and therefore no loving God. Despite its absurd contradictions, Lamar believes that there is some power in theological belief.
By comparing his own fate to that of Jesus in the Bible, Kendrick creates a religious allegory that demonstrates the power of belief in an imperfect God in the face of terror. He explores his fear of death, particularly his mindset around death growing up in a violent environment. “I’ll prolly die because these colors are standin’ out / I’ll prolly die because I ain’t know Demarcus was snitchin’ / I’ll prolly die at these house parties, fuckin’ with bitches / I’ll prolly die from witnesses leavin’ me falsely accused” (Lamar 59-62). Lamar’s fear of death is not only literal, but also figurative; he has existential dread around the idea of dying having lived a meaningless life, from meaningless, nihilistic or random causes. He turns to God for an answer to these questions, which results in a sort of religious allegory. Kendrick takes the position of a prophet, surrounded, as the Hebrew Israelites would say, by blasphemous people. He dies for the sins chosen by his social environment: for “fuckin’ with bitches,” for others bearing false witness. “Demarcus” is Judas from the bible: symbolizing the choice to betray Christ and the holy redemption. Kendrick sees the Christianity in his life, but denies embracing it fully due to the presence of evil in his life. He reaches a theological standstill which is irreconcilable yet universal; the contradictions within his belief reflect the contradictions within his life.
As a lyricist, Kendrick demonstrates his prowess for the art: he uses incantation, flashback storytelling, juxtaposition, and allegory to explicate the deep theological work of the Black Hebrew Israelites. He universalizes his experience in a way that most philosophers can’t, by making his work accessible and engaging the listener directly. The motifs are both evident and mysterious, by way of direct and symbolic references to his life. Themes of redemption intertwine with hope, fear, and dread. Above all, the work represents the contradictions of good and evil, belief and anguish, punishment and forgiveness. Lamar reflects on religion implicitly throughout the work, without resorting to the philosophical suicide that there is an all-loving God.
<strong>**Works Cited**</strong>
Kendrick Lamar Duckworth. “FEAR.” <em>DAMN, *Top Dawg Entertainment, 2017. *Spotify, **<a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/23luOrEVHMfoX0AhfbQuS6?si=ZX8VLju4TRChVODVbVRbmA">https://open.spotify.com/track/23luOrEVHMfoX0AhfbQuS6?si=ZX8VLju4TRChVODVbVRbmA</a></em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[**The Lord Shall Smite Thee!: Kendrick Lamar’s Problem of Evil** How could a loving God allow suffering? Theologians have considered such a question for hundreds of years. As one struggles through the senseless fears, abuses, and pains of life, it is only natural to question why an all-loving God would allow massive evil. Kendrick Lamar Duckworth, a contemporary rap artist, explores the implications of communicating evil in his track “FEAR.” from the 2018 Pulitzer Prize for Music winning album “DAMN.” The album as a whole employs grand instrumentals, creative lyricism, and experimental progrogression techniques to explore social issues that face the black community, and tangentially, Lamar’s reaction to his own successful life. “FEAR.” specifically centers around a fictional version of Kendrick and his uncle that share a distant yet caring relationship. The author is an artist and social critic, Lamar himself, addressing social issues in the world and in Compton; His foil is Carl Duckworth, Lamar’s cousin, a Balck Hebrew Israelite pastor in the Compton community. In his track, “FEAR.,” Lamar uses flashback storytelling, hymn-like incantation, and religious allegory, as well as juxtaposition with Judaic theodicies, in order to show that biblical suffering throughout his life contradicts the existence of an all-loving God. Lamar uses incantations that resemble religious prayer and preach in order to present the perspective that his life is in contradiction to the existence of an all-loving God. In his chorus, Lamar presents a plea to God which is sung both forwards and backwards. “Why God, why God do I gotta suffer? Pain in my heart carry burdens full of struggle” (Lamar 15-16) The voice of these lines is pleading to God for an answer; why must God allow Lamar to go through so much suffering? And if God is omnibenevolent as described by the prevailing religion in Lamar’s community, does that mean that Lamar’s suffering is illegitimate? It is implied that his pain is both physical and mental, and that has been continuous throughout his life. Perhaps Lamar has concluded that the religions around him provide no real answer to the problems that he faces, but that they do provide others with reassurance. It is also evident that Kendrick does not currently see his tribulations as justified, because he has attempted to love and engage with those around him. Lamar’s delivery is reminiscent of his implicit experiences in church, in that it reminds the listener of prayer or hymn singing. When repeated backwards, the lines transform into tongues, which allows the voice to change from Lamar’s into a more theologically knowledgeable identity. The song is meant to be interpreted as a critique of religion as a solution to non-existential fear, and its ability to solve immediate suffering. Ultimately though, the questions presented in the chorus as a whole set up a context for Kendrick’s rumination on his past. Duckworth also explicates the suffering of his early life through flashback storytelling and lyrical repetition, in order to prove its contrast to the belief in an omnibenevolent God. In the opening verse of the song, after Carl Duckworth has just called to explain the existence of God, Kendrick raps an imitation of his mother’s threats of violent punishment for wrongdoing during childhood. “Go back outside, I beat yo’ ass, lil’ nigga. That homework better be finished, I beat yo’ ass. Your teachers better not be bitchin’ ‘bout you in class” (Lamar 35-37) His mother here represents the God that judges and punishes him for doing poorly, which confuses young Kendrick. This recollection gives rise to the author’s theme that loving gods often have contradictory goals: here, for instance, his mother’s punishment gets in the way of his capacity to fulfill her requirements. Although she loves Kendrick, she uses violence as the answer. This is in his view flawed, and is the result of societal expectations (monetary value, education, etc.), perhaps in the same way that people project their own values onto the idea of god. Either way, Kendrick reminisces on the impact this had on his life: it created a sense of paranoia because his mother’s domestic abuse taught him perverse trust. This has caused him continuous “FEAR.” even to this day, hence the name of the track. Applied to theology, Kendrick shows that God is a construct of society, and that punishment by God is not loving or good, but instead perverse. The punishment by his allegorical God itself (violent beating) and its necessity mentioned by Carl show that the world is not Good, and instead apathetic to the phenomena of both good and evil. The poetic representation of the author’s difficult childhood is used as a means to juxtapose a hopeful existential belief in a higher power. The artist employs stark juxtaposition of his and Carl’s existential beliefs in order to demonstrate the absurdity of a belief in an all-good God. Lamar is explicitly discussing the themes of his music that are the most popular amongst listeners, specifically his existential fears of being an artist and living an improper life. “’Cause my DNA won’t let me involve in the light of God / I’m talkin’ fear, fear that my humbleness is gone / I’m talkin’ fear, fear that love ain’t livin’ here no more / I’m talkin’ fear, fear that it’s wickedness or weakness” (Lamar 110-113). The character here is discussing the implications of the Christian utopian mindset to strive for a better, more loving future. Here Carl’s ideology is juxtaposed with Kendrick’s childhood; his pedagogy and social pressure prohibits him from being holy. Furthermore, Carl’s identity as a Black Hebrew Israelite reveals to Kendrick that despite his success, there are still divine conflicts in his life. In Carl’s view Kendrick has an implied choice to resolve his fears: either go against the teachings of God, and be evil yet powerful and strong in the face of a difficult life, or follow them and find existential power yet lack social clout or the ability to defend himself from danger. Lamar attempts to resolve these contradictions in the line “Love ain’t living here no more” which has two interpretations. Either he must leave the cursed environment of his past in favor of an Enlightened future, or that there is no Enlightened future at all and therefore no loving God. Despite its absurd contradictions, Lamar believes that there is some power in theological belief. By comparing his own fate to that of Jesus in the Bible, Kendrick creates a religious allegory that demonstrates the power of belief in an imperfect God in the face of terror. He explores his fear of death, particularly his mindset around death growing up in a violent environment. “I’ll prolly die because these colors are standin’ out / I’ll prolly die because I ain’t know Demarcus was snitchin’ / I’ll prolly die at these house parties, fuckin’ with bitches / I’ll prolly die from witnesses leavin’ me falsely accused” (Lamar 59-62). Lamar’s fear of death is not only literal, but also figurative; he has existential dread around the idea of dying having lived a meaningless life, from meaningless, nihilistic or random causes. He turns to God for an answer to these questions, which results in a sort of religious allegory. Kendrick takes the position of a prophet, surrounded, as the Hebrew Israelites would say, by blasphemous people. He dies for the sins chosen by his social environment: for “fuckin’ with bitches,” for others bearing false witness. “Demarcus” is Judas from the bible: symbolizing the choice to betray Christ and the holy redemption. Kendrick sees the Christianity in his life, but denies embracing it fully due to the presence of evil in his life. He reaches a theological standstill which is irreconcilable yet universal; the contradictions within his belief reflect the contradictions within his life. As a lyricist, Kendrick demonstrates his prowess for the art: he uses incantation, flashback storytelling, juxtaposition, and allegory to explicate the deep theological work of the Black Hebrew Israelites. He universalizes his experience in a way that most philosophers can’t, by making his work accessible and engaging the listener directly. The motifs are both evident and mysterious, by way of direct and symbolic references to his life. Themes of redemption intertwine with hope, fear, and dread. Above all, the work represents the contradictions of good and evil, belief and anguish, punishment and forgiveness. Lamar reflects on religion implicitly throughout the work, without resorting to the philosophical suicide that there is an all-loving God. **Works Cited** Kendrick Lamar Duckworth. “FEAR.” DAMN, *Top Dawg Entertainment, 2017. *Spotify, **https://open.spotify.com/track/23luOrEVHMfoX0AhfbQuS6?si=ZX8VLju4TRChVODVbVRbmA]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tok Essay Response</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/01/TOK-Essay-Response.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tok Essay Response" /><published>2020-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/01/TOK-Essay-Response</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/01/TOK-Essay-Response.html"><![CDATA[<p>Within areas of knowledge, how can we differentiate between change and progress? Answer with reference to two areas of knowledge.</p>

<p>“Progress” is an axiological or a normative concept, which should be distinguished from such neutral descriptive terms as “change” and “development”<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> In normal terms, we as knowers ought to concern ourselves with progress for the sake of creating a specific future. This is a deeply modern idea: we all want to be on the cusp of a better tomorrow, endlessly striving for a marginally better tomorrow. This intention leeks over to thought itself; To know better is to do better. “What forms of change are qualified as progressive? How can we know which forms of knowledge to promote, in order to gain progress?” we may ask. To discover a new future this question must be settled. What will become clear in this discussion is that, because of the veil of the contemporary epoch, change is incredibly difficult to identify as progress on a short term basis. Instead, we must study how knowledge systems have quickly undergone expansions to their scopes, methods, and modes over time.
A competing model for understanding progress as distinct from change is the “progress as a form of change” theory. What quickly arises though, is the problem of momentous change as unprogressive, or minute changes as extremely progressive overtime. Knowers are rendered incapable, at least in the short term, to distinguish their progress in a field from a mere transformation, beyond a simple move towards a political ideal. We stagnate under this theory, since all knowledge is seen as relative and only liable to the judgement of history. However, from this problematic theory arises the possibility of epistemological technology: that is to say, knowledge of how an area of knowledge operates, expands, or contracts can enable us as knowers to manipulate those areas for our utopian goals.
We will soon find that the process of History is analogous to its study. But first let us ask: How does knowledge of history allow us to create a new future? Marx, in his study of the Napoleons, gives us an insight “Hegel remarks somewhere that all great world-historic facts and personages appear, so to speak, twice. He forgot to add: the first time as tragedy, the second time as farce.”<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> Indeed, it can be said that the normative study of history is essentially farce making: mimicking past events with new and perverted justifications or mimicking past justifications in new perverse events. To illustrate, at the 1974 Special Session of the U.N. General Assembly, Deng Xiaoping gave a speech which used Maoist ideology of anti-imperialism to justify privatizing the Chinese economy<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> . In other words, he used the ancienne Maoist justifications of “contradiction” to reify his project. In this way, he fails to depart from either the ideology of capitalism or communism, and instead simply creates a nominal “change.”
But in the end, what does it mean to depart from and progress beyond two antagonistic forces? This question is one of extreme import if we are to apply the knowledge borne by history, and construct a <em>present</em> as the children of the past. In fact, we may come to terms with the idea that History is a progression of opposing elements which develop alongside one another. As knowers, it is our job to find the weaknesses and strengths that align with our ideals and exploit them tirelessly in a political project. In his revolutionary project *A People’s History Of The United States, *Howard Zinn writes that American history is one of struggle between those who have “no respect for human rights or constitutional liberties” and those who fight politically for the tenets of “life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness.” Both groups of individuals have throughout time adapted and manifested, calculated and recalculated, all the while becoming more extreme and diverse alongside one another. Knowing history, in this light, entails a certain tactic: one of oppression or emancipation. Analogously, Dr. Ibram X. Kendi argues that racist and anti-racist ideologies have mutually progressed<sup id="fnref:4" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> . He cites the onset of racist poll taxes after electoral mobilization by the black liberation movement, and black political prisonhood after the decriminalization of enslavement, as being political action and reactions. The study of history, therefore, should not be viewed as some impersonal catalog of the facts. Contrarily, by documenting and debating history, we imply a departure from it. We as knowers declare in a very radical way that the struggle of one element or another throughout time will live on in us, and thus we simultaneously embody progress. History is progressive insofar as its study realizes the development of a transcendent utopia, but only as the prevention of an evermore imminent dystopia. Knowers can distinguish progress from change through the study of history, as they watch the prevalence of their ideal grow in unprecedented magnitude.
Perhaps we should begin by assuming Natural Science knowledge systems behave the same way - here being that through the “political” acts of data driven studies, high research output, and rigorously documented findings, we achieve the utopic outcome of scientific “advancement.” One such advancement in the near past, which caused a massive broadening of the scope and scale of knowledge in the natural sciences, was the discovery of quantum mechanics by physicists. After cathode rays were discovered, the black-body radiation problem was outlined; in response, more research led to the suggestion that energy states of particles could be discrete, they were modeled, and then photons were discovered. The work of 70 years culminated in an understanding of the elementary dynamics of quantum mechanics, whose groundbreaking technological applications in computer science (and particularly cryptography) can hardly be qualified as non-progressive.
But this discovery was hardly incremental. Actually, paradigms in science are shifted through massive imagination on the parts of audacious researchers: scientists who break the rules of “observation then hypothesis” in preference for hypothesis first, or who otherwise do “bad” science. They imagine a better world, one with a better understanding of an imagined concept, and then they prove their imagined solution to be true. Over time, we forgive their risk because it stands the test of rigor, reproduction, and time, and we perceive their work as progressive because it expands our horizons, even if it disrespected the methodologies of our area of knowledge. In the case of quantum mechanics,  Ludwig Boltzmann, in his postulation that energy states could be discrete, broke entirely with the paradigm of determinism in physics, in favor of probabilistic ones for prediction. Rather than tweaking the understanding of the day, by solving some absurdly trivial equation, or applying knowledge to some small sphere of human existence, this change proved different<sup id="fnref:5" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote" rel="footnote">5</a></sup> . In fact, it proved that “Bad science” can actually be progressive. While quality may be important in sustainable scientific change, one can  reject current paradigms of science  and make significant progress in advancing our horizon of understanding.
As Thomas Kuhn argues, progress also occurs when a change to a knowledge system begins to solve problems which the previous paradigm was unfit to address. The example which comes to mind is Peter Kropotkin’s theory of mutual aid evolution, which competes with Darwinian evolutionary theory. Kropotkin proposes that ecological systems change over time not with the forces of competition and selection, but rather under the mechanisms of cooperative action. Kropotkin accounts for symbiosis between organisms in his analysis, which was hitherto unexplained in the Darwinian school of thought, and answers the piling questions of non-selective ecological environments. Knowledge is technological in this way; it allows knowers to solve new problems, which the previous paradigm was unwilling or unable to address. But this does not always coincide with a wholesale rejection of the previous knowledge framework. Darwinian evolution still accounts for many situations, corroborating itself by mapping a specific territory of knowledge. Nonetheless, a new “map” has been charted, new problems can be anticipated and subsequently solved, and even more holes in the consensus understanding are found.
The ideals of epistemic progress operate differently between History and the Natural Sciences. Whereas history embeds a system of political justification and falsification into a seemingly benign and apolitical task of  “documentation,” the natural sciences purport to study phenomena which are related to the production of political technologies for the sake of  “the pursuit of knowledge.” Both systems, however, share an implicit connection to ethics: a more “known” world is a better one. Here, a more radical approach to the progress/change conversation erupts. “Change” in its rudimentary form is a way of sidestepping the epistemological, political, and ethical implications of one’s theory, by way of refurbishment or revitalisation; it is an attempt both in history and the natural sciences to appease critics with a “new” theory/technology which accounts for the issues, without addressing the root causes of the problem. Progress, on the other hand, is an acceptance of the implications of the theory, and an alignment between the utopia attempted and the world created by a form of knowledge.
Progress, throughout time, has been demarcated and defined by the rules of the epoch and its categories. Particularly, the questions we are fit to answer and the ones we are yet too meek to ask have waxed and waned with the years. In the study of history, not only does the salience of particular ideals constitute progress, but also the relationships between those values (epistemological, ethical, political, etc.) and the people who practice them. By studying, we position ourselves as agents of progress, whether that be the continuation of democracy, the elimination of oppression, or any other political agenda. By studying, we position ourselves as scientifically progressive by becoming aware of those phenomena as yet not understood and broadening the scope of the natural sciences in order to explain them.</p>

<p><strong>References</strong>
Flamm, D. (1997, October 7). <em>Ludwig Boltzmann – A Pioneer of Modern Physics</em>. arXiv.org. arXiv:physics/9710007
Deng, X. (1974).* Speech by chairman of the delegation of the People’s Republic of China, Teng Hsiao-ping, at the special session of the U.N. General Assembly,* April 10, 1974. Peking: Foreign Languages Press.
Kendi, I. X. (2016). <em>Stamped from the Beginning: The Definitive History of Racist Ideas in America</em>. Nation Books.
Marx, K., &amp; De, L. D. (1898). The eighteenth Brumaire of Louis Bonaparte. New York: International Pub. Co.
Niiniluoto, I. (1995a). Approximation in Applied Science. Poznan Studies in the Philosophy of the Sciences and the Humanities, 42, 127-139.
Zinn, H. (2010). Tyranny is Tyranny. In <em>A People’s History of the United States</em> (2010th ed., pp. 56-70). Harper Perennial Modern Classics.</p>

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>Niiniluoto, I. (1995a). Approximation in Applied Science. Poznan Studies in the Philosophy of the Sciences and the Humanities, 42, 127-139. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>Marx, K., &amp; De, L. D. (1898). The eighteenth Brumaire of Louis Bonaparte. New York: International Pub. Co. <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>Deng, X. (1974). <em>Speech by chairman of the delegation of the People’s Republic of China, Teng Hsiao-ping, at the special session of the U.N. General Assembly, April 10, 1974</em>. Peking: Foreign Languages Press. <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>Kendi, I. X. (2016). <em>Stamped from the Beginning: The Definitive History of Racist Ideas in America</em>. Nation Books. <a href="#fnref:4" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:5" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>Flamm, D. (1997, October 7). <em>Ludwig Boltzmann – A Pioneer of Modern Physics</em>. arXiv.org. arXiv:physics/9710007 <a href="#fnref:5" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Within areas of knowledge, how can we differentiate between change and progress? Answer with reference to two areas of knowledge. “Progress” is an axiological or a normative concept, which should be distinguished from such neutral descriptive terms as “change” and “development”1 In normal terms, we as knowers ought to concern ourselves with progress for the sake of creating a specific future. This is a deeply modern idea: we all want to be on the cusp of a better tomorrow, endlessly striving for a marginally better tomorrow. This intention leeks over to thought itself; To know better is to do better. “What forms of change are qualified as progressive? How can we know which forms of knowledge to promote, in order to gain progress?” we may ask. To discover a new future this question must be settled. What will become clear in this discussion is that, because of the veil of the contemporary epoch, change is incredibly difficult to identify as progress on a short term basis. Instead, we must study how knowledge systems have quickly undergone expansions to their scopes, methods, and modes over time. A competing model for understanding progress as distinct from change is the “progress as a form of change” theory. What quickly arises though, is the problem of momentous change as unprogressive, or minute changes as extremely progressive overtime. Knowers are rendered incapable, at least in the short term, to distinguish their progress in a field from a mere transformation, beyond a simple move towards a political ideal. We stagnate under this theory, since all knowledge is seen as relative and only liable to the judgement of history. However, from this problematic theory arises the possibility of epistemological technology: that is to say, knowledge of how an area of knowledge operates, expands, or contracts can enable us as knowers to manipulate those areas for our utopian goals. We will soon find that the process of History is analogous to its study. But first let us ask: How does knowledge of history allow us to create a new future? Marx, in his study of the Napoleons, gives us an insight “Hegel remarks somewhere that all great world-historic facts and personages appear, so to speak, twice. He forgot to add: the first time as tragedy, the second time as farce.”2 Indeed, it can be said that the normative study of history is essentially farce making: mimicking past events with new and perverted justifications or mimicking past justifications in new perverse events. To illustrate, at the 1974 Special Session of the U.N. General Assembly, Deng Xiaoping gave a speech which used Maoist ideology of anti-imperialism to justify privatizing the Chinese economy3 . In other words, he used the ancienne Maoist justifications of “contradiction” to reify his project. In this way, he fails to depart from either the ideology of capitalism or communism, and instead simply creates a nominal “change.” But in the end, what does it mean to depart from and progress beyond two antagonistic forces? This question is one of extreme import if we are to apply the knowledge borne by history, and construct a present as the children of the past. In fact, we may come to terms with the idea that History is a progression of opposing elements which develop alongside one another. As knowers, it is our job to find the weaknesses and strengths that align with our ideals and exploit them tirelessly in a political project. In his revolutionary project *A People’s History Of The United States, *Howard Zinn writes that American history is one of struggle between those who have “no respect for human rights or constitutional liberties” and those who fight politically for the tenets of “life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness.” Both groups of individuals have throughout time adapted and manifested, calculated and recalculated, all the while becoming more extreme and diverse alongside one another. Knowing history, in this light, entails a certain tactic: one of oppression or emancipation. Analogously, Dr. Ibram X. Kendi argues that racist and anti-racist ideologies have mutually progressed4 . He cites the onset of racist poll taxes after electoral mobilization by the black liberation movement, and black political prisonhood after the decriminalization of enslavement, as being political action and reactions. The study of history, therefore, should not be viewed as some impersonal catalog of the facts. Contrarily, by documenting and debating history, we imply a departure from it. We as knowers declare in a very radical way that the struggle of one element or another throughout time will live on in us, and thus we simultaneously embody progress. History is progressive insofar as its study realizes the development of a transcendent utopia, but only as the prevention of an evermore imminent dystopia. Knowers can distinguish progress from change through the study of history, as they watch the prevalence of their ideal grow in unprecedented magnitude. Perhaps we should begin by assuming Natural Science knowledge systems behave the same way - here being that through the “political” acts of data driven studies, high research output, and rigorously documented findings, we achieve the utopic outcome of scientific “advancement.” One such advancement in the near past, which caused a massive broadening of the scope and scale of knowledge in the natural sciences, was the discovery of quantum mechanics by physicists. After cathode rays were discovered, the black-body radiation problem was outlined; in response, more research led to the suggestion that energy states of particles could be discrete, they were modeled, and then photons were discovered. The work of 70 years culminated in an understanding of the elementary dynamics of quantum mechanics, whose groundbreaking technological applications in computer science (and particularly cryptography) can hardly be qualified as non-progressive. But this discovery was hardly incremental. Actually, paradigms in science are shifted through massive imagination on the parts of audacious researchers: scientists who break the rules of “observation then hypothesis” in preference for hypothesis first, or who otherwise do “bad” science. They imagine a better world, one with a better understanding of an imagined concept, and then they prove their imagined solution to be true. Over time, we forgive their risk because it stands the test of rigor, reproduction, and time, and we perceive their work as progressive because it expands our horizons, even if it disrespected the methodologies of our area of knowledge. In the case of quantum mechanics, Ludwig Boltzmann, in his postulation that energy states could be discrete, broke entirely with the paradigm of determinism in physics, in favor of probabilistic ones for prediction. Rather than tweaking the understanding of the day, by solving some absurdly trivial equation, or applying knowledge to some small sphere of human existence, this change proved different5 . In fact, it proved that “Bad science” can actually be progressive. While quality may be important in sustainable scientific change, one can reject current paradigms of science and make significant progress in advancing our horizon of understanding. As Thomas Kuhn argues, progress also occurs when a change to a knowledge system begins to solve problems which the previous paradigm was unfit to address. The example which comes to mind is Peter Kropotkin’s theory of mutual aid evolution, which competes with Darwinian evolutionary theory. Kropotkin proposes that ecological systems change over time not with the forces of competition and selection, but rather under the mechanisms of cooperative action. Kropotkin accounts for symbiosis between organisms in his analysis, which was hitherto unexplained in the Darwinian school of thought, and answers the piling questions of non-selective ecological environments. Knowledge is technological in this way; it allows knowers to solve new problems, which the previous paradigm was unwilling or unable to address. But this does not always coincide with a wholesale rejection of the previous knowledge framework. Darwinian evolution still accounts for many situations, corroborating itself by mapping a specific territory of knowledge. Nonetheless, a new “map” has been charted, new problems can be anticipated and subsequently solved, and even more holes in the consensus understanding are found. The ideals of epistemic progress operate differently between History and the Natural Sciences. Whereas history embeds a system of political justification and falsification into a seemingly benign and apolitical task of “documentation,” the natural sciences purport to study phenomena which are related to the production of political technologies for the sake of “the pursuit of knowledge.” Both systems, however, share an implicit connection to ethics: a more “known” world is a better one. Here, a more radical approach to the progress/change conversation erupts. “Change” in its rudimentary form is a way of sidestepping the epistemological, political, and ethical implications of one’s theory, by way of refurbishment or revitalisation; it is an attempt both in history and the natural sciences to appease critics with a “new” theory/technology which accounts for the issues, without addressing the root causes of the problem. Progress, on the other hand, is an acceptance of the implications of the theory, and an alignment between the utopia attempted and the world created by a form of knowledge. Progress, throughout time, has been demarcated and defined by the rules of the epoch and its categories. Particularly, the questions we are fit to answer and the ones we are yet too meek to ask have waxed and waned with the years. In the study of history, not only does the salience of particular ideals constitute progress, but also the relationships between those values (epistemological, ethical, political, etc.) and the people who practice them. By studying, we position ourselves as agents of progress, whether that be the continuation of democracy, the elimination of oppression, or any other political agenda. By studying, we position ourselves as scientifically progressive by becoming aware of those phenomena as yet not understood and broadening the scope of the natural sciences in order to explain them. References Flamm, D. (1997, October 7). Ludwig Boltzmann – A Pioneer of Modern Physics. arXiv.org. arXiv:physics/9710007 Deng, X. (1974).* Speech by chairman of the delegation of the People’s Republic of China, Teng Hsiao-ping, at the special session of the U.N. General Assembly,* April 10, 1974. Peking: Foreign Languages Press. Kendi, I. X. (2016). Stamped from the Beginning: The Definitive History of Racist Ideas in America. Nation Books. Marx, K., &amp; De, L. D. (1898). The eighteenth Brumaire of Louis Bonaparte. New York: International Pub. Co. Niiniluoto, I. (1995a). Approximation in Applied Science. Poznan Studies in the Philosophy of the Sciences and the Humanities, 42, 127-139. Zinn, H. (2010). Tyranny is Tyranny. In A People’s History of the United States (2010th ed., pp. 56-70). Harper Perennial Modern Classics. Niiniluoto, I. (1995a). Approximation in Applied Science. Poznan Studies in the Philosophy of the Sciences and the Humanities, 42, 127-139. &#8617; Marx, K., &amp; De, L. D. (1898). The eighteenth Brumaire of Louis Bonaparte. New York: International Pub. Co. &#8617; Deng, X. (1974). Speech by chairman of the delegation of the People’s Republic of China, Teng Hsiao-ping, at the special session of the U.N. General Assembly, April 10, 1974. Peking: Foreign Languages Press. &#8617; Kendi, I. X. (2016). Stamped from the Beginning: The Definitive History of Racist Ideas in America. Nation Books. &#8617; Flamm, D. (1997, October 7). Ludwig Boltzmann – A Pioneer of Modern Physics. arXiv.org. arXiv:physics/9710007 &#8617;]]></summary></entry></feed>